怎么样，史波克？
Well, Mr. Spock?
很标准，舰长
Very typical, captain.
铁硅地表，氢氧大气
Iron-silicon base, oxygen-hydrogen atmosphere,
无生命特征，一切正常
largely arid, no discernible life. No surprises.
制图组，开始扫描
Cartographic section, begin scanning.
与视觉小组988-TG，22号机组联机，呼叫完毕
Tie in to visual section 988-TG, computer bank 22. Kirk out.
大概再绕轨道4圈就够了，莱斯利
About four more orbits ought to do it, Mr. Lesley. That'll wrap it up.
准备前往第200号星际基地
Lay in a course for Starbase 200.
是的，舰长
Aye, aye, captain.
舰长
Captain.
- 史波克！ - 难以置信，舰长
- Mr. Spock! - Incredible, captain.
刚才发生了什么？
What was that?
仪器读数令人震惊，舰长
What my instruments read is totally unbelievable, captain.
有两次，每次只有一瞬间
Twice, for a split second each time,
仪器能监测到的所有物质
everything within range of our instruments
似乎都到了消失的边缘
seemed on the verge of winking out.
- 我要你告诉我真相，不是吟诗！ - 我说的就是真相，舰长
- I want facts, not poetry! - I have given you the facts, captain.
这个星系的磁场发生了瞬间转换
The entire magnetic field of this solar system simply blinked.
根据我们的测量，下面这颗行星的
The planet below, the mass of which we are measuring,
质量是零
attained zero gravity.
那不可能
That's impossible.
- 你所说的… - 是不可能的
- What you're describing... - Is nonexistence.
舰长，星舰指挥部发来通用警告信号
Standard general alert signal from Starfleet Command, captain.
所有单位进入警备，各就各位
All stations to immediate alert status. Stand by.
舰长，扫描器侦测到星球表面有一个生物
Captain, scanners now report a life object on the planet surface below.
5分钟前就进行了全面生命检测
You just did a complete life survey five minutes ago.
- 为什么你现在才发现生命迹象？ - 无法解释
- How is it you're picking it up now? - Inexplicable.
这数据是在刚才那场
This reading began at approximately the moment
磁力转换消失之后才出现的
that the pulsation phenomenon began to subside.
那么那个物体
Well, what is it, this object?
- 是什么东西？ - 一个生物
- Its physical makeup? - A living being.
98.5华氏度，存在生物电活动，正在活动
Body temperature, 98.5 Fahrenheit. Mass, electrical impulses, movement.
很显然是人类，舰长
It is apparently human, captain.
而他的出现…
And its appearance...
恰好是宇宙接近“消失”的时候？
...coincided with this cosmic "winking out"?
几乎是在同一秒
Almost to the second.
- 你的解释是？ - 没有
- Explanation? - None.
你觉得他会威胁到星舰吗？
Speculation? Could this being present any danger to the ship?
有可能
Possible.
非常可能
Very possible.
乌乎拉上尉，通知安全部
Lieutenant Uhura, notify Security
派遣一支武装队伍和我们一起登陆
to have an armed detachment of men ready to beam down with us.
出发，如果星舰指挥部有任何指令
Let's go. Any word comes through from Starfleet Command,
立即发送过来
pipe it down immediately.
通信优先级，一级
Communications, priority one.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages Of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命和新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilisations,
勇敢地航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
TLF荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：Nick
校对：喜马拉雅
第一季第二十五集
替换因素
舰长日志，星历3087.6
Captain's log, stardate 3087.6.
在侦查一个未知行星时
While investigating an uncharted planet,
进取号，以及整个象限的宇宙空间
the Enterprise, and at least this entire quadrant of space,
都遭受到一股剧烈而不可解释的力量
has been subjected to violent, unexplained stress and force.
探测器显示这个星球上有一个人类
Sensors have reported the presence of a human being on the planet below
也许他和这次事件有关
who might be connected with the phenomenon.
我与我的大副现正带领一支部队
With my first officer and a security team,
前去搜寻此人
I have set out in search of him.
你们来了！
You came!
谢天谢地，还有时间
Thank the heavens. There's still time.
现在还不晚
It's not too late.
我们还可以阻止他，但是我…
We can still stop him, but I...
但我需要你们的帮助
But I need your help.
还没有消息，长官
Nothing yet, sir.
- 双锂晶体出现状况了 - 怎么了？
- Report on the dilithium crystals. - Yes?
之前发生的那个现象
Whatever that phenomenon was,
几乎耗干了晶体能量，可能有麻烦了
it drained almost all of our crystals completely. It could mean trouble.
你真会轻描淡写，上尉
You have a talent for understatement, lieutenant.
如果晶体能量不足，星舰10小时之后就会开始下坠
Without full crystal power, our orbit will begin to decay in ten hours.
- 立即提高功率 - 遵命，长官
- Reamplify immediately. - Aye, aye, sir.
- 有发现其他磁场紊乱吗？ - 还没有，舰长
- Any further magnetic disturbance? - Negative, captain.
- 扫描仪显示情况正常 - 没有异常？
- Scanners indicate situation normal. - Nothing?
是的
Nothing.
太奇怪了，这么强大的效应
Illogical. An effect of such proportions,
居然无法以任何已知的物理定律解释
unexplainable by any established physical laws that I'm aware of.
虽然不清楚这场效应的本质
I have been able to ascertain one fact.
但我能确定，它的影响范围很广
Though the effect, whatever it was, was unquestionably widespread,
我们脚下的星球反应最强烈
it was strongest here, on the planet beneath us.
继续侦查
Keep checking.
星舰指挥部一分钟前发来了红二信号，舰长
Red Two message in one minute, captain. Starfleet Command.
代码因子1，长官
Code Factor 1, sir.
- 重复 - 代码因子1
- Repeat. - Code Factor 1.
遭到入侵
Invasion status.
全体船员，这是舰长，进入战斗状态，进入战斗状态
All hands, this is the captain. Battle stations. I repeat, battle stations.
这不是演习
This is no drill.
我是麦考伊，舰长
McCoy, captain.
- 我是寇克 - 我们的病人…
- Kirk here. - About our patient...
- 怎么了，快讲 - 他没有什么大碍
- Yes, doctor, quickly. - He'll make it.
他受了点伤，暂时不能活动，但会康复的
He'll be stiff and sore for a while, but he'll be all right.
我等下再和他谈谈，谢谢你，呼叫完毕
I'll talk to him later. Thank you, Kirk out.
可以接受信息了，舰长
Message ready, captain.
接入大屏幕
Main screen coming on.
我是寇克，进取号已准备就绪，准将
Kirk here. Enterprise standing by, commodore.
一小时前你已发现那场效应
You're aware of the effect an hour ago.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
但你可能还不知道它的影响范围
You may not be aware of its scope.
它波及了银河系全部象限并且范围远不止如此
It occurred in every quadrant of the galaxy and far beyond.
完全破坏了正常的磁场和重力场
Complete disruption of normal magnetic and gravimetric fields.
还导致了时间扭曲以及异常的辐射改变
Time warp distortion, impossible radiation variations,
而你们现在正处于
and all of them centring in the general area
这场效应的中心位置
which you are now patrolling.
问题就在于，这到底是一场自然现象
The question is, are these natural phenomena?
还是人为引发的？如果是后者，谁造成的？
Or are they mechanically created? And if they are, by whom?
目的又是什么？你怎么看，舰长
For what purpose? Your guess, captain.
谢谢，长官
Thank you, sir.
我已经想过所有可能
I have considered all the alternatives.
但我觉得这最可能是侵略的前奏
My best guess is it could be a prelude to invasion.
我们也一致认为
Exactly our consensus.
我现在需要你查明情况
I'm giving you the job of finding out specifically.
遵命，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
能给我再分配一艘星舰作预备队吗？
Can you assign me other starships as a reserve?
不行
Negative.
我现在要撤离距你100秒差距内的
I'm evacuating all Starfleet units and personnel
所有星舰和船员
within 100 parsecs of your position.
这对你和进取号来说是一项艰巨的任务
It's going to be tough on you and the Enterprise,
但现在你们只能靠自己了
but that's the job you've drawn. You're on your own.
我明白了
I see.
你是要让我们做诱饵
You mean we're the bait.
- 祝你好运 - 谢谢，长官
- Good luck. - Thank you, sir.
让所有作战单位保持警觉
Maintain alert status at all battle stations.
- 遵命，长官 - 我们来分析一下，史波克
- Aye, aye, sir. - From the top, Mr. Spock.
第一，那场效应来自我们下面这个星球
First, the phenomenon came from the planet below.
第二，这次危机是真实而且迫切的
Secondly, the danger is apparently real and imminent.
第三，需要对星球表面进行一次更细致的侦查
Third, a closer examination of the planet surface would be in order.
- 我来吗，长官？ - 是的
- My job, sir? - Yes.
而我，将会和我们的不速之客谈谈
Meanwhile, I'll talk to our unexpected guest.
或许他能回答我的一些问题
Maybe he can provide some answers.
就是这样，我登陆了那个星球
That's how I came to be down there, captain.
去追捕那个恶鬼
Pursuing the devil's own spawn.
我已经在宇宙里追寻了许久
A thing I've chased across the universe.
他外表是人
He's humanoid outside,
但其实他是个杀人如麻的恶鬼
but inside he's a hideous, murdering monster.
我会抓到他的，舰长，我发誓
I'll get him, captain. I swear it.
你说这个人
You say this one man--
不是人！
Not man!
是恶鬼
Thing.
这个恶鬼，毁灭了你的文明
--thing, destroyed your entire civilisation.
- 杀死了所有男人，女人还有儿童 - 那你是怎么逃脱的？
- To the last man, woman and child. - How did you escape?
我当时在检查通讯卫星
I was inspecting magnetic communication satellites.
你相信我的，是吧？
You believe me, don't you?
在我们找到你之前
Before we picked you up,
我们的星舰遭遇了一些奇异的效应
our ship sustained a number of incredible effects.
是他！他就是死亡，是所有生命的公敌
That was he! He's death, antilife.
他为毁灭而生！
He lives to destroy!
是他袭击了你吗？
Is he the thing that attacked you?
是的
Yes.
我保证，我发誓
I give you my word. I swear it.
我们还没有掌握其他详细的情况
We don't have any other facts, any information.
那么你会帮助我吗？
Then you'll join me in my holy cause?
让他接受正义的审判和复仇
Help me in visiting justice and vengeance upon him?
我只关心舰队安危和完成任务
My only cause is the safety of my ship and the mission we're on.
你和我一起下去，看看你说实话了没有
You'll beam down with me, I'll check your story out.
史波克，有什么发现吗？
Spock, find anything?
没有，舰长，我们的客人有情况吗？
Negative, captain. Anything from our guest?
据他所说，这里有个类人生物
According to him, there's a creature of some sort down here, a humanoid.
乌乎拉上尉传达了这个消息
Lieutenant Uhura communicated that information.
我用机器重新检测了
I ordered reconfirmation on our sensors.
但没有发现生命迹象
They indicate no living creature on this planet.
舰长，我认为他没有说实话
I suggest, captain, that you've been lied to.
舰长，你说过这只有一种解释
Captain, you yourself said there were no other explanations.
你凭什么要相信这个人？
Why do you give credence to this man?
我不理解你为什么生气
I fail to comprehend your indignation, sir.
我只是做了一个合理的推测，认为你是个骗子
I have simply made the logical deduction that you are a liar.
把真相告诉我们吧
Let's have it. The truth this time.
你回来了是吧？我在这！
You've come back then, is it? Well, don't stop! Here I am!
来啊！我们来做个了结！
Come at me again! We'll finish it!
- 能确认情况吗？ - 我在试，舰长
- Can you identify that? - Trying, captain.
拉萨勒斯！
Lazarus!
你待在这，所有人，红色警报
You stay here. All personnel, Security Red.
来！来！这对你没有好处！
Come! Come! It'll do you no good!
我会追你追到天涯海角！
I'll chase you into the very fires of hell!
- 拉萨勒斯 - 我又看到了
- Lazarus, what happened? - I saw it again.
那个东西，他袭击了我
The thing. It attacked me.
我们走
Let's get out of here.
舰长，数据显示，效应的中心在这个星球
Captain, readings of the effect indicate it's centred here on this planet,
几乎就在我们现在的位置
almost on this very spot.
我跟你说了就是那个恶鬼！
I told you it was a thing!
一片黑白的虚空，令人恐惧的虚空
All white, black and empty, a terrible emptiness.
我们回到星舰上去吧
Let's get back to the ship.
如果我们不先杀了他，他会把我们都杀了
He'll kill us all if we don't kill him first!
杀！杀！杀！杀！杀！
Kill! Kill! Kill! Kill! Kill!
舰长日志，星历3088.3
Captain's log, stardate 3088.3.
我们仍环绕着这个荒芜的星球飞行
We continue to orbit the dead planet,
那场影响了进取号和整个银河系的效应
which seems to be the source of the phenomenon
似乎就来源于这个星球
which has struck the Enterprise and all sections of the galaxy once again.
至于拉萨勒斯
As for Lazarus,
他所说的那个类人生物仍旧困扰着我
the story he tells me about the humanoid continues to trouble me.
- 有新发现吗？ - 没有，舰长
- Any luck? - Negative, captain.
对于第二场效应
I can no more explain the occurrence
它的起因应该跟第一场一致
of the second phenomenon than I can the first.
如果拉萨勒斯所说的是真的话
If there's a shred of truth to what Lazarus said...
难道真的会有这样的类人生物
That a single creature, a humanoid,
能够引发这么巨大的效应？
could be responsible for an effect of such magnitude?
- 难以置信 - 确实
- Hard to believe. - Indeed.
但他的情况似乎并不矛盾
But the rest of his story seems to fit.
他的伤势说明他遇到了袭击
His wounds testify to an apparent confrontation with something.
- 是的 - 假设真有这么个类人生物
- Affirmative. - Assuming there is a humanoid,
他是怎么做到的？
a something, how does he do it?
他没有武器，没有能力
He has no weapons, no power.
舰长，我只知道那场效应发生的时间
Captain, I only know for certain that the occurrence of the phenomenon
恰好与拉萨勒斯声称
coincides exactly with the moments
他受到袭击的时间相一致
that Lazarus has his alleged confrontations.
麦考伊医生想见你，舰长
Dr. McCoy asking to see you in Sickbay, captain.
我不确定，吉姆
I don't know, Jim.
也许是我出现了幻觉，但也许不是
Maybe I'm imagining things and maybe I'm not. You tell me.
说吧，你叫我来想说什么
You tell me. That's why you brought me down here, isn't it?
我们一起带拉萨勒斯回来的
Well, as you know, we both brought Lazarus in here,
我处理了他额头上一道很深的伤口，对吧？
and I treated a deep abrasion on his forehead, right?
- 是的 - 然后我包扎了一下
- Right. - And then I bandaged it,
我刚进入这间房…
I stepped into this room for just a moment...
老骨头，我还有很多事要做，说重点
Bones, I've got a lot of things to do. Get to the point.
好吧，假设他即使有爬行动物的体质
Well, say he's got the constitution of a dinosaur.
具有强大的再生能力
Recuperative powers, ditto.
再加上我这个神医的妙手
And as we both know, I'm a bright young medic with a miraculous touch.
那也不至于在我回来的时候
Why then, when I returned, there wasn't a trace
他额头上连伤痕都没有吧？
of that wound on his forehead?
连淤青都没有，就像他没受过伤
Not even a bruise. It was like he had never been injured.
他在哪？
Where is he?
我不知道，吉姆，这是艘大船
I don't know, Jim. This is a big ship.
而我只是个医生
I'm just a country doctor.
- 嗨 - 嗨，喝点咖啡？
- Hi. - Hi. Coffee?
那是命令吗，上尉？
Is that an order, lieutenant?
我知道你想说什么
I know what you mean.
双锂晶体功率提升了吗？
Reamplification finished on the dilithium crystals?
已经准备就绪了
Yeah, ready and waiting.
拉萨勒斯，你还好吗？
Lazarus, you all right?
是的
Yes.
但已经没耐性了
But impatient.
你决定好要帮我了吗？
Have you decided to help me yet?
- 怎么了？ - 没什么
- Something wrong? - No.
我们这医生的幽默感有点特别
I have a ship's physician with a strange sense of humour.
不是的，吉姆，我没看花眼
No, but this is no joke, Jim. I know what I saw.
舰桥呼叫舰长
Bridge calling the captain.
- 说 - 希望你能到舰桥来一下
- Go. - Request you come to the bridge.
- 有什么发现吗？ - 有些异常情况
- Find something? - Something quite extraordinary.
我来了，拉萨勒斯，跟我来
On my way. Lazarus, you're with me.
老骨头，有空的时候我会笑两下
Bones, if I had time, I'd laugh.
打开主屏幕，上尉
Main screen on, lieutenant.
屏幕已经开启了，先生
Screen on, sir.
一个放射源，舰长
A source of radiation, captain.
为什么扫描仪之前没有检测到？
How is it the scanners didn't pick it up before?
因为它之前不在那里
Because it is not there.
又一个玩笑？先是麦考伊，然后是你
Another riddle? First Dr. McCoy, then you.
我想说的是，根据我们正常的扫描程序
What I mean is that, according to our usual scanning procedures,
之前没有任何能制造出读数的东西
there's nothing there that could be causing that effect.
但现在却出现了
But it is there.
是的，我承认，我有点无话可说了
Affirmative. I confess I am somewhat at a loss for words.
虽然有点轻率和不严谨，但我们可以…
It may be described, though loosely and inaccurately...
…姑且将其看作宇宙中的一道裂口
...as a rip in our universe.
- 什么？ - 是某种物理扭曲，舰长
- A what? - A kind of physical warp, captain,
在其扭曲范围内，目前已知的所有物理定律都不适用
in which none of our established physical laws apply with any regularity.
但我借助双锂晶体定位了它
However, with the dilithium crystals, I was able to localise it.
是的！是的！
Yes! That's it!
双锂晶体
The dilithium crystals.
它们的力量
Their power.
- 我们能做到！ - 你是说那个类人生物？
- We could do it! - You refer to the humanoid?
是的，我们能对付他了，舰长
Yes. We've got him, captain, we've got him.
这和晶体有什么关系？它们只找到一个辐射点
What do crystals have to do with it? All they show is a point of radiation.
就是这样，这是关键
That's just it. That's the key.
可以用它们来抓住他，那就是对策
That's the way to trap him. That's the solution.
舰长…
Captain...
…我请求你，我恳请你
...I beg of you. I plead.
- 我要求你，把晶体给我 - 不可能
- I demand. Give me the crystals. - Out of the question.
那些晶体是这艘星舰的能源核心
Those crystals are the very heart of the power of my ship.
你这个白痴
You fool.
如果不杀了他，你将会失去你的星舰
There won't be any ship if we don't kill him.
- 他会毁灭你们所有人 - 怎么毁灭？
- He'll destroy all of you. - How?
快告诉我！你说的话全都含糊不清
Now, you tell me how! All I've heard from you is double talk, lies, threats,
一点实际意义都没有，现在你告诉我
accusations, they don't hold an ounce of water. Now, you tell me,
他为什么会威胁我的星舰？
how does it present a danger to my ship?
我警告你，舰长
I warn you, captain.
- 你必须把晶体给我 - 别威胁我，拉萨勒斯
- You'll give me the crystals. - Don't threaten me, Lazarus.
我没有在威胁你
No threat intended.
舰长…
Captain...
…我会报仇的
...I'll have my vengeance.
马斯特斯上尉，舰长找你
Lieutenant Masters, captain's calling.
我是马斯特斯
Masters here.
你能在10分钟内准备好一间实验室吗？
Can you prepare an experimentation chamber in ten minutes?
将双锂晶体功率设至最大
All dilithium crystals full power.
我看看，舰长
I'll check, sir.
舰长，实验室将在10分钟后准备完毕
Captain, the chamber will be ready in ten minutes, sir.
我的助手和我会…舰长！
My assistant and I will-- Captain!
- 舰长！ - 上尉，怎么了？
- Captain! - Lieutenant, what is it?
发生什么事了？上尉！上尉！
What's wrong? Lieutenant! Lieutenant!
舰长，安全部报告说拉萨勒斯失踪了
Captain, Security reports Lazarus missing.
舰长日志，星历3088.7
Captain's log, stardate 3088.7.
我们对所遭遇的这几次效应的研究
We are no closer to finding an answer
并没有什么新的进展
to the strange phenomenon than we were at the beginning.
不仅有两个船员被袭击
Not only have two of my crewmen been attacked,
还有两块双锂晶体也不见了
two of our dilithium crystals are missing,
现在进取号无法以最大功率运行
and without them, the Enterprise cannot operate at full power.
必须找到它们
They must be found.
第一：你说你需要那些晶体
Fact: You said you needed the crystals.
第二：就在一个小时之后，它们不见了
Fact: An hour after you said you must have them, they were missing.
第三：我的两个船员被袭击了！
Fact: Two of my crewmen were attacked!
事实是，舰长，我没有拿那些晶体
And fact, captain: I didn't take the crystals.
不是我
I'm not the one.
找到我的敌人
Find my enemy.
找到那只禽兽，你就能找到晶体
Find the beast, and you'll find the crystals.
那这只禽兽是怎么上我的船的？
How did this beast get aboard my ship?
- 他的确上来了 - 不，他没有被传送上来
- He did. Isn't that enough? - No. He didn't transport up.
仪器会记录每次传送
A report would've been made.
他有能力摧毁整个世界啊
I tell you we're dealing with a creature capable of destroying worlds.
为什么他需要那些晶体？
Why does he need the crystals?
- 为什么？ - 为了和我一样的目的
- For what reason? - For the same reason that I do.
听我说
Listen to me.
他是类人生物
He's humanoid.
他会驾驶宇宙飞船
Why, he can pilot a spaceship.
他懂得如何消灭一个种族！
He can compute formulas to destroy races!
他需要水晶给座驾提供能量，逃离我的追捕
He can steal an energy source for his vehicle so he can escape from me.
- 难道你们又聋又瞎吗？！ - 坐下
- Are you deaf as well as blind?! - Sit down.
晶体显然不在这里
The crystals certainly aren't here.
星球上有个未知的辐射源
There's an unexplained radiation source on the planet.
显然这两者有些联系
Obviously some connection.
我们会找到答案的，立即组织一支搜寻队伍
We'll check it out. Organise a search party immediately.
- 拉萨勒斯会和我们一起出发 - 谢谢，舰长
- Mr. Lazarus will beam down with us. - Thank you, captain.
我们还不一定会找到什么
You may not have reason to thank me...
所以你先不用急着谢我
...depending on what we find.
你现在怎么看，舰长？
What do you believe now, captain?
我相信那些晶体不在你的船里
I believe the missing crystals aren't in your ship.
- 史波克？ - 无法定位辐射源
- Mr. Spock? - Unable to locate the radiation source.
为什么？你不是在进取号上找到了吗？
Why not? You had it spotted from the Enterprise.
它消失了，舰长
It has simply disappeared, captain.
我要彻底搜查这块区域
I want every inch of this terrain checked.
找寻足迹，和所有可疑的东西
Look for footprint, movement, anything.
如果找到了，进行呼叫，允许使用武器
Call out if you spot anything. Don't be afraid to use your weapons.
舰长！小心！
Captain! Look out!
他醒过来了
He's coming out of it now.
那个恶鬼
The thing.
没事了，你在进取号上
It's all right. You're onboard the Enterprise.
- 那块石头，我 - 你的头怎么样了？
- The rock, I-- - How's your head?
疼
Aches.
你救了我的命，谢谢你
You saved my life down there, I wanna thank you.
我责无旁贷
Why shouldn't I?
我要问你些问题
I have some questions I want to ask you.
- 现在还不行，吉姆 - 我必须问
- Not now, Jim. - It's necessary.
问吧，没事的
Go ahead, it's all right.
这里有一份报告
This is a computer report...
针对你的第一次审查所做
...of the evidence you gave at your first screening.
但结果表明，你在说谎
It calls you a liar, Lazarus.
首先，调查显示，你所说的星球根本不存在
For one thing, there's no planet at the location you said you came from.
也从来没有
There never has been.
如果你要我们帮忙，最好讲实话
If you want help from us, you better start telling the truth.
- 如果我告诉你们，你们肯定不会相信的 - 说吧
- You wouldn't believe me if I told you. - Try us.
好吧
All right.
我撒谎是为了让自己可以全身而退
I distorted a fact in the interest of self-preservation for my holy cause.
我需要的是帮助，是自由
I needed help, not censure.
而不是作为一个疯子受到责难和监禁
Freedom, not captivity for being a madman.
我怕说出真相就会遭到那些对待
I was afraid that's what you'd call me if I told you the truth.
我现在就告诉你们真相
I'll have the truth now.
我的星球，我的地球…
My planet, my Earth...
…或者说，它的遗迹…
...or what's left of it...
…就在我们下面
...is down there beneath us.
你在说什么？
What are you saying?
我的宇宙飞船可不只是一般的飞船
My spaceship is more than just that.
它还是一个时间机器
It's a time chamber. A time ship.
而我，是一个时空旅行者
And I, I am a time traveller.
那你在追捕的恶鬼也是时空旅行者？
And this thing you search for is a time traveller too?
是的
Oh, yes.
他为了逃脱我的追捕，不断穿越时空
He's fled me across all the years.
到达了一个渺无生机的…
All the empty years, to a dead future...
…早已被他摧毁的星球的未来
...on a murdered planet he destroyed.
帮帮我，把晶体给我，我要杀了他
Help me. Give me the tools I need to kill him, the crystals.
别让他跑了，别让他跑了
Don't let him get away. Don't let him get away.
拉萨勒斯你受伤了，我明白了，我很同情你
Lazarus, you've been hurt, I know, I sympathise.
但我还要考虑到我的430名船员
But I've got 430 other men to worry about.
- 那些晶体在哪？ - 我说了，在他那里
- Now, where are those crystals? - I told you, he's got them.
他拿了晶体，那个恶鬼，那个恶鬼
He took them. The thing. The thing.
他需要休息，吉姆
He's got to get some rest, Jim!
还有，你能让这个肌肉男离开我的病房吗？
And would you get that muscleman out of my Sickbay?
- 那个恶鬼 - 解散
- The thing. - Dismissed.
- 他很痛苦 - 有时痛苦比快乐更容易产生动力
- He's in a lot of pain. - Sometimes pain can drive a man
我相信你明白的，医生
harder than pleasure. I'm sure you know that, doctor.
别担心，我不会让他跑掉的
Well, don't worry, he's not going anywhere.
至少这次不会
Not this time.
我们现在都有哪些未解之谜，史波克？
What do we got, Mr. Spock?
能够触发消失现象的磁场效应？
A magnetic effect which produces a winking-out phenomenon?
星球上的那个神秘的未知辐射源？
A mysterious, unidentified source of radiation on the planet?
暴脾气的拉萨勒斯，你所谓的宇宙裂缝？
Lazarus, a walking powder keg, your rip in the universe?
还有那个所谓的恶鬼？
A so-called murdering humanoid?
是的，但更让我困惑的是
True, captain, but more significant to me
我们船上的设备专门用来
is the fact that our ship's instruments are specifically designed
对宇宙中的任何东西定位和定性，不管是能量还是物质
to locate and identify any object in our universe, be it energy or matter.
但这些设备
But by using those instruments,
却没办法提供那个辐射源的信息
you were unable to identify the source of the radiation on the planet.
是的，这似乎有问题
Correct, which would seem to be impossible.
- 仪器运作正常吗？ - 非常正常
- Are the instruments in order? - Perfect working condition.
那么据你所说，只有一种可能性了
Then what you say leads obviously to one alternative.
那个辐射源并不是来自我们的宇宙
The source of radiation is not from our universe.
也不在我们的宇宙里面
Nor in our universe, captain.
他来自外界
It came from outside.
外界？
Outside?
是的
Yes.
这样就解释得通了
That would explain a lot.
另一个宇宙，或者说另一个维度
Another universe, perhaps in another dimension...
占据着同一时空的另一个维度
...occupying the same space at the same time.
平行宇宙存在的可能性
The possible existence of a parallel universe
已经被科学所证实了，舰长
has been scientifically conceded, captain.
好的
All right.
如果说…
What would happen if...
另一个宇宙，一个负宇宙
...another universe, say, a minus universe...
和我们身处的正宇宙相遇会如何？
...came into contact with a positive universe such as ours?
无疑会发生强烈扭曲，物理定律都会失效
Unquestionably, a warp, a distortion of physical laws, on an immense scale.
而那正是我们经历过的
Which is what we've been experiencing.
它们相遇的那个点…
The point where they come into contact...
似乎可以描述成一个洞
...couldn't that be described as a hole?
的确，而且我认为，宇宙中若存在这么一个洞
Indeed. I point out that a hole in the universe,
就会像所有洞一样，既可以漏出
or in a simple container, can either allow the contents to escape...
也可以流进
Or what is outside to enter.
正如巴斯托准将所担心的入侵
The invasion that Commodore Barstow suspected.
但没有大规模入侵的迹象
But there has been no evidence of a large-scale invasion.
小规模入侵呢，史波克？
But a small-scale invasion, Mr. Spock?
你对拉萨勒斯的精神状况评估如何？
What is your analysis of the mental state of Lazarus?
很难评估，舰长，他一时偏执狂妄
Difficult, captain. One moment paranoid,
一时又冷静理性
the next, calm, mild, rational.
就好像是…
Almost as if he were...
- 两个人 - 是的，两个人
- ...two men. - Yes, two men.
相貌相同，但人格迥异
Different but identical.
还有我们所说的这个洞，不，是门
And a hole in the universe. No, not a hole, a door.
这两个人可以穿过这扇门
Through which these two beings are somehow enabled to pass.
看看拉萨勒斯吧，前一分钟他还濒临死亡…
Take a look at Lazarus. One minute he's at the point of death...
…但下一分钟又变得健康强壮了
...the next he's alive, well, strong as a bull.
开始他额头受了伤，后来伤痕消失了，现在又出现了
The cut on his forehead, first he has it, then it's gone, then he has it again.
这对一个正常人来说是不可能的
Which is physically impossible for one man.
没错，毫无疑问，有两个拉萨勒斯
Quite right. Unquestionably, there are two of him.
但究竟是怎么回事？
But what's going on?
穿越不同的宇宙…
This leaping from universe to universe...
说出有个恶鬼摧毁了文明这样的疯话
...this wild talk about a murdering creature who will destroy civilisations,
到底是为了什么？
what's the purpose?
吉姆，疯狂无需动机
Jim, madness has no purpose...
也无需理由
...or reason.
但可以有目的
But it may have a goal.
我们必须阻止他，必要的话甚至要消灭他
He must be stopped, held, destroyed if necessary.
- 我不明白 - 两个平行的宇宙中
- I don't follow you. - Two parallel universes project this,
必有一个是正宇宙，另一个是负宇宙
one positive, the other negative.
更准确地讲，一个是物质的…
Or, more specifically, one matter...
…一个是反物质的
...the other antimatter.
你知道你在说什么吗？
Do you know what you're saying?
物质和反物质相遇时会泯灭
Matter and antimatter have a tendency to cancel each other out, violently.
更准确地说，在一定情况下
Precisely. Under certain conditions...
当正物质和反物质粒子相遇时
...when two identical particles of matter and antimatter meet.
就像拉萨勒斯
Like Lazarus.
相同的
Identical.
两个拉萨勒斯
Like both Lazarus...
一个是正物质，另一个是反物质的
...only one is matter and the other antimatter.
如果他们相遇…
If they meet...
会发生湮灭反应，吉姆
Annihilation, Jim.
彻底的，绝对的湮灭反应
Total, complete, absolute annihilation.
任何地方的任何东西
Of everything that exists...
都会消失
...everywhere.
警告：高压电
增能器短路了
The energizer, it's shorted.
- 离开这里！拉响警报！ - 走，上尉，一起走
- Get out of here! Sound the alarm! - Come on, you too, lieutenant.
- 不，我必须 - 我们该走了！
- No, I've gotta-- - We've gotta go!
整个机组可能都会被烧毁
The whole bank might blow.
轮机部呼叫舰桥
Engineering calling bridge.
起火了！起火了！
Fire! Fire!
供能装置短路了
The energising circuits.
起火了，舰长，轮机部有紧急情况！
Fire, captain, Engineering. Situation critical!
所有人，赶紧跟我来，还有史波克
All available personnel, on the double. Spock, with me.
- 报告情况 - 已经控制住了，长官
- Report. - Under control, sir.
- 但这绝不是自发故障 - 拉萨勒斯为了获得晶体做了手脚
- But it couldn't have started by itself. - Lazarus. A trick to get the crystals.
先生，你不能进来
Sir, you shouldn't be in here.
是吗
Oh, I didn't know.
他可能正带着晶体准备下船，我要抓住他
He's probably beaming down with the crystals right now. I'm going after him.
你安排好安全事项，马上来找我
You organise a security detail. Follow me as soon as you can.
史波克呼叫舰桥
Spock to bridge.
我就要抓住你了，我要打开通道了
I'll get you now. I have a threshold.
尽管跑吧
Run, run.
我会抓住你的
I'll get you now.
启动
Energize.
好了，好了，快好了
It's done. It's done. Finished, finished. It's done.
好了
It's done.
好了，好了
It's done, it's done.
- 拉萨勒斯 - 好了
- Lazarus. - Done.
不！不！不是你！
No! Don't! Not you!
不！
No!
欢迎，舰长
Welcome, captain.
没想到你来了
I wasn't expecting you.
你以为会是他吧
No. Him.
是的
Yes, him.
你已经知道了
You understand.
还不是太清楚
Not completely.
这是平行宇宙吗？
This is a parallel universe?
是的
Of course.
- 这里是反物质的 - 是的
- Antimatter. - Here, yes.
如果相同的粒子相遇了…
And if identical particles meet...
一切都会消失
The end of everything.
文明，物质，都会湮灭
Civilisation, existence, all gone.
我想要阻止他，舰长
I tried to stop him, captain.
所以我拿了你们的晶体
That's why I took your dilithium crystals.
他有两个
He has two more.
糟糕了，舰长
That's very bad, captain.
如果等他自己过来的话…
If he comes through at a time of his own choosing...
但我想，如果抓紧时间，你帮我一把
But I think, if we hurry, and you will help me...
…我们还是能阻止他的，时间已经不多了
...he can yet still be stopped. There's little time left.
他本想过来
He meant to come through.
但当你闯入时，消耗了晶体能量
When you accidentally passed through, it drained his crystals.
他要重新提取能量
It will take him about ten minutes to re-energize
大概需要10分钟
with equipment aboard his ship.
那点时间应该够了
That should give us enough time.
我到底是通过什么来到这里的？
Exactly what did I pass through?
这很难解释，舰长
That's hard to explain, captain.
我将之称为替换翘曲
I call it an alternative warp.
它是连接两个平行宇宙的负磁性通道
It's sort of a negative magnetic corridor where the two parallel universes meet.
有点像安全阀
It's sort of a safety valve.
保证两个世界不会因为相接触而爆炸
It keeps eternity from blowing up.
这个通道…
This corridor...
…就是引起那场磁场效应
...is it what caused the magnetic effect,
让一切接近消失的原因吗？
the winking-out phenomenon?
是的，但这并不是由它的出现而引起的
Precisely, captain, but not because of its existence.
而是…因为另一个我进入了你的宇宙
Because... Because my foe entered.
那条通道就像是一间门上有炸弹的牢房
The corridor is like a prison with explosives at the door.
如果打开门，炸弹就会爆炸
Open the door, and the explosives might go off.
如果待在里面…
Stay inside...
宇宙就会安全
And the universe is safe.
两个宇宙，舰长
Both universes, captain.
你的和我的
Yours and mine.
拉萨勒斯肯定知道，如果你们两个人在
Surely Lazarus must realise what would happen
通道外面相遇，会发生什么吧
if you should meet face-to-face outside the corridor.
他当然知道了，舰长，但他疯了
Of course he knows, captain, but he's mad.
你已经听过他的疯言疯语了，他丧失理智了
You heard him. He's lost his mind.
当我们的科学家发现了通过这个通道的方法
When our people found a way to slip through the warp
并且证明了另一个平行宇宙的存在
and prove another universe, an identical one, existed
他没办法接受这一切
it was too much for him.
他不能容忍我的存在
He could not live knowing that I lived.
开始想方设法追杀我
He became obsessed with the idea of destroying me,
就算这要搭上他自己的性命…
and the fact that it meant his own destruction and everything else...
…他也在所不惜
...meant nothing to him.
所以，你就是他所说的那个杀人如麻的恶鬼
So you're the terrible thing, the murdering monster, the creature.
是的，舰长…
Yes, captain...
…但可能他才是
...or he is.
仁者见仁，智者见智了，不是吗？
Depends on your point of view, doesn't it?
准备好了，舰长
It's ready, captain.
如果我们可以把他逼进通道
If we can force him into the corridor
我会在那里等着他，做个了结
while I'm waiting for him, we can put an end to this.
但如果由他自己择机进入通道
But if he comes through at a time of his own choosing,
并且来到这个宇宙找到我…
and breaks into this universe to find me...
我明白了
I understand.
你要我做什么？
What do you want me to do?
找到他
Find him.
把他逼进通道
Force him through his threshold
而我会在通道里面等他
while I'm waiting for him, into the corridor.
- 我会在那里制服他 - 这只能暂时控制他
- And I'll hold him there. - You can't hold him forever.
是吗，舰长？
Can't I, captain?
你要摧毁他的飞船
You destroy his ship.
但如果我摧毁了他的飞船，你的也会被摧毁
But if I destroy his ship, won't yours also be destroyed?
- 是的 - 那你的门就会被关闭了
- It will. - And your door will be closed.
是的，他的门也会被关闭
Yes, and so will his.
你会和他永远被困在通道里
You'll be trapped inside that corridor with him forever.
互相厮杀
At each other's throats throughout time.
相比两个宇宙的安全来说…
Is it such a large price to pay...
这个代价很大吗？
...for the safety of two universes?
我准备好了
I'm ready.
把他给我送过来
Send him to me.
我会等着
I'll be waiting.
拉萨勒斯
Lazarus.
退后！
Stand back!
不！不！不，我还没准备好！
No! No! No, I'm not ready!
我还没准备好！
I'm not ready!
把晶体带回进取号
Take these crystals to the Enterprise.
我必须摧毁这艘飞船
I must destroy that ship completely.
- 拉萨勒斯会怎么样？ - 他还能怎样？
- What of Lazarus? - And what of Lazarus?
启动相位炮组
Activate phaser banks.
相位炮组已启动
Phaser banks activated.
准备开火
Stand by to fire.
相位炮准备就绪，长官
Phasers standing by, sir.
开火
Fire phasers.
好的，莱斯利，我们走吧
All right, Mr. Lesley, let's get out of here.
- 启程，1级曲速 - 遵命，长官
- Ahead, warp factor 1. - Warp 1, sir.
史波克，我们会没事的
Everything's all right, Mr. Spock, for us.
但他们没有退路了
There is, of course, no escape for them, sir.
是的，不会再有了
There is, of course, no escape.
和一个想杀了你的疯子…
How would it be...
…一起被困在一个地方，直到永远…
...trapped forever with a raging madman at your throat...
…会是什么样的感觉？
...until time itself came to a stop. For eternity.
到底会是什么样的感觉？
How would it be?
舰长
Captain...
至少宇宙安全了
...the universe is safe.
对你和我来说是的
For you and me.
但拉萨勒斯呢？
But what of Lazarus?
拉萨勒斯呢？
What of Lazarus?
TLF字幕组欢迎你，欢迎有志之士加入
TLF中文字幕站http://tlfsubs.eastgame.org/